All right. So, we've already talked
about how to give some output. So, let's
talk about how to get some input. So,
the way we're going to do this is we're
going to use the keyword prompt. This
shows a dialogue on screen that gathers
information from the user through the
keyboard. The message we're going to say
is, "What is your username?"
And I'm going to put a semicolon on the
end of this. Semicolons are optional in
JavaScript, but you should be in the
habit of using them because it will make
your life simpler later on. So, we're
going to say prompt, what is your
username? If we come over, we now see we
have a pop-up box. Unlike an alert box,
this box has a text box where the user
can enter information. So, I'll say,
what is your username? Bruce Wayne. And
hit enter. Um, so great, we've gathered
our first piece of input, but where did
that input go? If we come back over to
our Visual Studio Code, um, we can see
that if we want to store information, I
have up here how we would store
information. I create a variable. I give
the variable name and then I put
information inside of it. So this first
name is storing the information to
store the information entered by the
user into the prompt. We're going to do
a similar thing as we did on the line
above. So I'm going to create a
variable. I'm going to say let I'm going
to give that variable name username and
I'm going to say equals and then
whatever the user types into this
prompt. So, I'm going to gather the
information from the user over the
keyboard and I'm going to store it in
this variable called username.
Um, so just to prove to you that this
does in fact work, we're going to use
something from the last video and we're
going to use an alert box to display it.
So, when we type alert and we put the
open parenthesis, an alert can take in a
message of any type. The message I want
to show is whatever is inside of
username. So, I could just hardcode text
here and say hello world. or I can use
my variable and I can display what's
inside of my variable. So I'm going to
use the word username. So now what my
program is going to do is it's going to
take in information. It's going to store
it in a variable and then it's going to
display whatever is being stored in that
variable. So if we save this and we come
over here, it says what is your
username? I could put I am Batman. And
if I hit okay, the alert box pops up. I
am Batman. And so now we have
successfully gathered input, stored it
in a variable, and displayed it. If we
come back over to our Visual Studio
Code, I'm going to show you one more
thing that you can do with prompt box.
So when you first created your prompt,
if you put an opening parenthesy, it
gives you this helpful little message
that says message question mark colon
string. This means a prompt can take in
a message and the type of message it
needs to take in is a string. So unlike
an alert box which can take in any type
of information, this message can only
take in a prompt can only take in a
string, not an integer, not a float, it
has to be a string. Um, then you'll
notice that there's this comma here and
then it gives you another keyword called
default and then the question mark. So
what the question mark means is that
this piece of information is optional,
but you can provide it. If you provide
it, the um prompt box will use that
information. So, just to show you what
this does, we'll say, okay, we know we
can take in an information, and that
information can be a string. So, I'm
going to say, uh, what is your username?
And then we're going to put a comma just
like the comma up here in the hint box.
And then it says default. And this also
needs to be a string. So, I'm going to
put the word test here. And I'm going to
show you what this does. So, if we save
this and we come over, we see we now
have the prompts box, but instead of
being an empty text box here for the
user to type in, we've pre-supplied some
information. So, this might help if
you're having a user enter in
information and you know some of the
information already, you can display it
and then they can correct it. So, I
could change this from being test to I
am Batman or I could leave it as test.
Um, and so that is how the default
portion works. If we don't provide that
portion, I'm going to save my code. We
come back over here and we reload our
page. Um, we can see that there is
nothing provided in the text box. So,
the second thing that you send to the
prompt box, totally optional, but it
allows you to put a default message
there. And that concludes this video.
Thanks for watching.